So you're in high school physics class
And your teacher asks the class
Okay everyone what is the formula for
Momentum
And you being an eager young physics
Student raise your hand
And proudly tell your teacher that
Momentum equals mass
Times velocity and your teacher says
Great job
That is exactly right momentum equals
Mass times velocity
And the whole class claps and cheers for
You because you got the answer right
And you go up to the front of the class
And your teacher gives you a gold star
For being such a good physics student
And that night you go home
And your parents are there and they say
We hear you got an answer right
In physics class today and so we decided
To celebrate your birthday
Six months early and then they give you
An xbox
And so you stand proudly with your xbox
In one hand
And a copy of a brief history of time by
Stephen hawking in the other
And you tell yourself that this is the
Best day of your life
So you graduate high school with amazing
Grades and then the day finally comes
When you go to university to study
Physics
And you're really excited because you
Are going to become a scientist
You show up to your mechanics class and
The professor asks
What is the formula for momentum and you
Tell your professor momentum equals mass
Times velocity
And then your professor gives you an
Angry look and she says
You complete idiot this isn't some
Physics class for dumb babies
We are studying rotational mechanics and
In rotational mechanics an object's
Momentum is defined using the inertia
Tensor
Which is a symmetric 3x3 matrix that you
Can calculate by doing integrals over
The mass distribution
And the whole class of 300 people laugh
At you for getting the answer wrong
And for being a dumb idiot and you ask
Yourself if you are really meant to be a
Physics student after
All maybe you are too much of a dumb
Idiot to study physics
You go home that night and desperately
Search the internet to figure out what
The inertia tensor is
But you just get lost in a maze of
Wikipedia articles and feel more
Confused than when you started you
Remember that day when your high school
Teacher told you that you were right for
Saying that momentum
Equals mass times velocity and you
Wonder why your high school physics
Teacher lied to you
And why they didn't tell you about the
Inertia tensor the next day you show up
At your relativity class
And your professor is albert einstein
And einstein tells you that momentum is
A four-dimensional vector that lives in
Four-dimensional space-time
And you tell einstein that you thought
Momentum was calculated with the
Three-by-three symmetric inertia tensor
And einstein is like well technically
Rotational angular momentum is a
Four-dimensional bivector but that's
Outside the scope of this course
Later you go to your advanced mechanics
Class and your professor tells you that
Generalized momentum
Conjugate to position is defined as the
Partial derivative of the lagrangian
With respect to q
Dot and in hamiltonian mechanics
Momentum is just a coordinate in the
Phase space
On a symplectic manifold and then you go
To your quantum physics class and the
Professor says that momentum
Measurements are always probabilistic
And the way to get the expected value of
Momentum is to operate on the
Wavefunction with the momentum operator
Which has the square root of negative 1
In it for some reason
And then do an integral over all
Possible outcomes and also the momentum
Wave function might be the fourier
Transform of the position wave function
But he can't be sure since everything is
Just probabilities
At this point you've completely given up
Trying to understand what momentum is
You've stopped going to classes and
You've stopped doing your homework
Because life is pointless and physics
Will never
Make sense no matter how hard you try
You remember back to the greatest day of
Your life when your high school physics
Teacher gave you a gold star
And you remember now that your teacher
Had this tired look in her eye
A quiet sadness that you couldn't
Explain and that's when you realize
She knew she knew that momentum wasn't
Equal to mass times velocity
Because she had gone to university to
Study physics just like you
And she lied to you to protect you from
The truth
Because she didn't want you to deal with
The pain of never knowing what momentum
Is because it's too complicated
And you realize that students all over
The world are in high school right now
Being lied to being told that momentum
Is mass times velocity
And they too will go to university and
Learn the truth and suffer just like you
Did
And you clench your fists in anger you
Realize that the eternal cycle of folly
Needs to be stopped and it's time to
Destroy momentum once and for all
So you go to switzerland and dig a
Tunnel to the large hadron collider
And you're about to push the secret
Button on the large hadron collider that
Will destroy the universe
But then the avengers show up to stop
You and captain america tells you that
He understands how you feel
And that we've all been there we've all
Been confused in physics class
And think that we're dumb but the way to
Deal with pain isn't to destroy the
Universe
Instead we should help others and use
Our life experience to make the world
Less painful
For future generations and iron man says
He wants
Shawarma anyway the avengers beat you up
And the police arrest you and when
You're in court the judge sentences you
To life in prison for trying to destroy
The universe which is the worst possible
Crime
So you're sentenced to life in a
Frictionless vacuum
Eternally bouncing off the walls of your
Cell in perfectly elastic collisions
And all you can think about is whether
You should calculate your momentum with
An inertia tensor or a lagrangian or a
Wave function
And you will never know the answer
Happy april fools normally i use this
Channel to teach math and physics
You can check the description for links
To my playlists on
Tensors for beginners tensor calculus
Error correcting codes
And relativity i actually just finished
A video series on special relativity
And i'm about to start general
Relativity so feel free to subscribe if
You want to watch my general relativity
Videos when i upload them